<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arvind Ram Sankar</title>
    <description>You are at Arvind's Personal Website</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 12:39:17 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 12:39:17 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Internet Privacy: Proxy Servers and VPN</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Privacy is a huge concern on the internet, especially when there are companies making billions by selling users data. In this article, I’ll be mainly talking about Proxy servers and VPN, two of the most common ways to maintain anonymity on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;incognito-doesnt-work&quot;&gt;Incognito Doesn’t Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all you out there who might think that you are completely anonymous if you use incgnito mode, well guess what, you are wrong. Incognito mode is only good at preventing anyone with access to your computer from easily finding your activities. It clears all the browsing history, all the cookies so that anyone using your computer will not be able to see what you did. But the rest of the internet can still see what you are doing. The website that you just accessed in incognito mode still knows your location and so does your internet service provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://whatismyipaddress.com/&quot;&gt;What is My IP Address&lt;/a&gt; to see what others on the internet see your location as. Now the whole point is, we need something better to hide ourself and protect our privacy. Now, before we look at what proxy and VPN is, let’s try to get a general understanding of how internet works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ## How internet works


![How internet works](/assets/images/frcnn.png)

So, your mobile phone is connected to the wifi. Let’s say you open the browser and type https://google.com. When you enter the url on your browser and press search, your phone starts sending packets of information to the wifi access point in your house. Then it travels to the modem through the ethernet cable. Your modem would probably have fiber connection or something similar that was provided to you by your internet sevice provider. Through this channel. The packets travel to your internet service provider, in this case, airtel. Now your ISP performs an IP lookup. All the nodes in a network are identified using their IP address, the ISP gets the IP address of the server of google through a DNS lookup. THen it transmits the packets through routers to google’s server. Google’s server receives the packet, processes the request and sends back the response. This is how a one way trip to the server takes place.
 --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-private-is-internet&quot;&gt;How private is internet?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you open the browser and type https://google.com. When you enter the url on your browser and press search, your phone starts sending packets of information through the wi-fi router. These packets contain information about the source and destination in their header. This is obvious because all the nodes in the network need this information in order to route the packet from source to destination and vice versa. But this means that all the nodes in the network can see where the packet came from and where it is going to. That is why you are able to google and find information about your public IP address and your IP’s location. The only thing preventing the internet from pinpointing your exact location is the NAT setup by the ISP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the server you are communicating with has lots of information about you. Therefore, anything you do on the web can easily be traced back to you. There is absolutely zero privacy there. And as we saw, incognito doesn’t work in this case because all incognito does is delete you history and session cookies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s have a look at what a Proxy is and how it offers privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;proxy-server&quot;&gt;Proxy Server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proxy here serves the exact same purpose as it’s definition, which is a substitute, or someone else who represents you.
We often hear people using the word proxy in the context of accessing blocked websites. For example, In my school computers, websites like youtube,facebook are blocked by a firewall. We often used proxies to bypass the firewall. A proxy server essentially acts as your substitute and fetches content from the internet for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/proxy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Proxy Server&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This image shows how we can use a proxy to access the blocked facebook website. In this case, the firewall believes that you are communicating with some server and allows you to do it. But this server inturn communicates with facebook and fetches content on your behalf and sends it over to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But proxies are more than just means to bypass firewalls, they also provide a certain degree of privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proxy-and-privacy&quot;&gt;Proxy and Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A proxy essentially acts as your gateway to the internet. Now, there are different types of proxies offering different levels of security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Transparent proxy&lt;/strong&gt; is the least secure. It simply forwards the request they get and they are the least secure. They don’t try to hide the users IP address and just forward whatever request they get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anonymous proxy&lt;/strong&gt; takes your request and replaces the source IP with it’s own IP. So when you access facebook, as far as the rest of the internet is concerned, it’s just proxy accessing facebook. The facebook servers will receive the Proxy’s IP and they don’t have any clue about who is on the other side of the proxy. But the disadvantage with anonymous proxies is that they don’t hide the fact that they are proxies. If some sites choose to deny service to proxy users, you won’t be able to visit them while using an anonymous proxy. Since anonymous proxies do hide your IP address, they’re not a bad choice if you’re looking to gain a bit of control over your online privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider &lt;strong&gt;High anonymity proxies&lt;/strong&gt; — also known as elite proxies — a step up from your regular anonymous proxy. The fundamentals are the same, except high anonymity proxies also disguise your use of the proxy itself. A website won’t be able to detect that you’re using a proxy if you use one of these. High anonymity proxies achieve this added protection by periodically altering your new IP address and also withholding any clues that they are serving as proxies on your behalf. They’re the most secure type of proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proxy can be further improved by caching websites, filtering content etc which provides extra speed and security. But proxy is not 100% secure. So, do proxies not maintain privacy on the internet? Well, upto a certain extent. Highly anonymous proxies do provide a high degree of privacy.  But proxies definitely aren’t 100% secure. Someone with access to the proxy server can easily get information about all the transactions and can trace back to the user. And one more important thing to remember is that a proxy can only provide privacy for the things that you do on your browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;virtual-private-network&quot;&gt;Virtual Private Network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Proxies provide a decent level of privacy, the only thing they are good at is hiding your IP address. VPNs are a step above Proxies as they can hide your IP address and provide an encrypted connection too!
VPNs provide “device protection” and it protects all your  traffic, including your browser, wherever you have a VPN installed and enabled. VPNs provide added security and privacy for all your online activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that the internet is a public resource, so what exactly does a private network mean here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-private-network&quot;&gt;What is a Private network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to wikipedia, a private network is any connection within a specified network wherein restrictions are established to promote a secured environment. In a more simpler term, a network can be configured in such a way that devices outside the network cannot access it. But the devices within the network can access contents outside the private network. So yes, your home wifi is a type of private network. If you check your IP, it’ll probably show something like 192.168.something.something or 172.something.something.something. These are your private IP addresses. All the devices connected to the same wi-fi network can access you through this address. But devices outside the network cannot access your system using this IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Virtual Private Network&lt;/strong&gt; (VPN) extends a private network across a public network and enables users to send and receive data across shared or public networks as if their computing devices were directly connected to the private network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this VPN technology was actually developed to provide access to corporate applications and resources to remote or mobile users, and to branch offices. Later, for security, the private network connection started using an encrypted layered tunneling protocol, and users were required to pass various authentication methods to gain access to the VPN. Now, VPN is also used for privacy on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s have a look at what VPN is and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-vpns-work&quot;&gt;How do VPNs work?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to note is that VPN completely removes your Internet Service Provider (ISP) out of the picture. Instead of routing the packet to the destination through your ISP, we establish a secure connection to one of the VPN nodes/servers. If you open a VPN application, you usually see different countries listed. So these are the available VPN nodes. The VPN service providers like Nord VPN etc sets up a network of servers all over the world. When you choose a server, the VPN client app that you downloaded establishes a secure tunnel connection from your device to the server bypassing ISPs or any other person who might be lurking in the network. THe VPN service provider use various algortihms like IPSec to encrypt the connection and provide protection at IP level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your device is now seen as being on the same local network as your VPN. So your IP address will actually be the IP address of one of your VPN Provider’s servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A VPN connection usually works like this. Data is transmitted from your client machine to the connected node in the VPN network through a secure tunnel. The VPN node receives the packets and all relevant information, it then encrypts your data and sends it through the internet. Another node in the VPN network decrypts your data and sends it to the appropriate internet resource, maybe a web server, an email server, or your company’s intranet. Then the internet resource sends data back to a point in your VPN network, where it gets encrypted. That encrypted data is sent through the internet to another point in your VPN network, which decrypts the data and sends it back to your client machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings us to the next question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-secure-are-vpns&quot;&gt;How secure are VPNs?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like with any online software or service, the security of a VPN will be reliant on a number of factors. In the case of VPNs, these factors include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The kind of technology the VPN provider uses&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;There are different protocols for establishing secure connections. IPsec is one. There are other protocols such as OpenVPN, Secure Socket Tunneling Protocol  etc. Most of these protocols are fool proof and do provide a good amount of security.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The laws in your country and the VPN provider&lt;/strong&gt;
Throughout this connection process, your identity is only revealed to the VPN node that you get connected to. Most of the VPN providers usually keep a log of all the connections to their network. Based on the laws surrounding VPN, the VPN provider might be forced to submit the user history if forced to do so. In countries like China, VPN is completely banned and you can be put into jail for using it. VPN use is also banned completely in Belarus, North Korea and Iraq.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vpn-vs-proxy&quot;&gt;VPN vs Proxy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference can be summed up in a single sentence &lt;em&gt;“A proxy is just a gateway whereas a VPN is a tunnel”&lt;/em&gt;. Another thing to note is that a connection to proxy goes through your ISP, so it is still possible to trace back to you. In the case of a VPN, only the VPN node knows your identity, which is known to the VPN service provider. As long as the VPN provider keeps it safe, your data will be 100% private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is 100% true. There is nothing that provides complete privacy. The Internet is all about connecting all the devices in the world, and if you access something over the internet it can always be traced back to you. The only thing that matters is how easy it is to trace back to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a normal internet connection is like sitting in your house with a door open, if you consider the fact that HTTPS is encrypted, it’s similar to sitting in your house with your door closed, but not locked. Anyone can open it. Using proxy locks the door, but there is still a back door that can be used to get into your house. VPN locks all the doors but the person who has the key can definitely enter your house. So it depends on how safe the key is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end nothing is completely private. It’s just a matter of how easy  you make it for others to dig up stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/internet-privacy-proxy-servers-and-vpn/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/internet-privacy-proxy-servers-and-vpn/</guid>
        
        <category>network privacy</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>internet</category>
        
        
        <category>Privacy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Arvind's Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new blog. I’ll be posting a lot of interesting stuff here. Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-i-switched-from-medium-to-a-custom-website&quot;&gt;Why I switched from Medium to a Custom Website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I rip-off a “Medium” looking template instead of writing articles on Medium itself? Well, that’s because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-its-a-custom-website&quot;&gt;1. It’s a custom website!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a web developer, there is nothing better than having a website which you have total control of. I can do whatever I want with it and modify it however I want, no holds barred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, Medium has a very good template, color scheme and font. Hence this “Mediumish” template. A huge shoutout to &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/wowthemesnet/mediumish-theme-jekyll&quot;&gt;Mediumish &lt;/a&gt; for developing this awesome template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-people-can-read-more-than-5-times&quot;&gt;2. People can read more than 5 times&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the obvious drawback of Medium is that it only allows users to read five free articles a month. That’s fair considering that the authors also need to earn. And since my main motive for writing this blog isn’t money, I don’t need to have any such limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-advanced-technical-stuff&quot;&gt;3. Advanced Technical Stuff&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I am familiar with things like JAMStack, Search Engine Optimization and hosting websites, I find this pipeline to be easier. I host my website on Netlify, which allows me to even use custom domain and provides free SSL certificates. I can do my own SEO and don’t need Medium’s help and I use markdown with Jekyll (JAMStack) which is extremely easy to work with. I can also branch out my domain name into various subdomains and host all kinds of things here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, since I’m tech savvy, this is fairly easy for me and has more advantages than Medium. So here we are! I’ll be posting a lot of stuff (hopefully) on this website now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-new-blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-new-blog/</guid>
        
        
        <category>General</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Write beautiful reports in Markdown using Pandoc</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor. If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, I’ll be talking about how to write beautiful reports in markdown using pandoc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preview&quot;&gt;Preview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be using this template for making our repor
As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;html&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;ml-1 mr-1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;target=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;_blank&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fab fa-twitter&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;css&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-css highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#999988&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;font-style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;italic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#a61717&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#e3d2d2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;js&quot;&gt;JS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// alertbar later&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scroll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scrollTop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;280&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;.alertbar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fadeIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;.alertbar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fadeOut&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;python&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'redcarpet'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Redcarpet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;to_html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;c&quot;&gt;C&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-c highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/writing-beautiful-reports-in-markdown/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing-beautiful-reports-in-markdown/</guid>
        
        <category>markdown</category>
        
        <category>report</category>
        
        <category>pandoc</category>
        
        
        <category>Misc</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tracking Without Bells and Whistles</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article talks about a completely new paradigm of object tracker. And what’s special about this tracker is that it requires only an object detector and nothing else! No additional training or additional algorithm is required for tracking objects. Hence the name tracking without bells and whistles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can checkout the complete research paper at &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1903.05625&quot;&gt;arXiv.org&lt;/a&gt;. This article gives an overview of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tracking-by-detection&quot;&gt;Tracking by detection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking by detection is a paradigm of object tracking algorithm that use an object detector as a basis for performing object tracking. Modern Object detectors such as YOLO and FRCNN are able to achieve extremely high accuracy with very low computation time. Therefore, we might as well use object detectors for performing tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracking by detection can be essentially simplified to the following three steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Perform object detection on frame at time &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Perform object detection on frame at time &lt;em&gt;t+1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Map the objects detected in frame &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt; to the objects detected in frame &lt;em&gt;t+1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/det-tracking.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tracking by detection&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third step is known as &lt;strong&gt;data association&lt;/strong&gt; as it involves associating objects detected in one frame to that of another. There are various algorithms for performing data association. We can also use different types of object detectors for performing the object detection step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several object trackers such as SORT and deepSORT use this paradigm of object tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;revisiting-object-detector&quot;&gt;Revisiting Object Detector&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to understand how this new object tracker works, we need to go back to the basics and understand how single and multiple object detectors work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;single-object-detector&quot;&gt;Single Object Detector&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a CNN based object detector, we generally have a VGG backbone network which converts an image into feature maps. We stretch out these features maps into a fully connected layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![Object detection with CNN](/assets/images/obj-det-cnn.png){ width=50% } --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/obj-det-cnn.png&quot; alt=&quot;Object Detection with CNN&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we can use the Fully Connected Layer to perform a classification based on class label and a regression for bounding boxes. You can read more about this on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you pass an image to object detector the output looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/obj-det-res.png&quot; alt=&quot;Result of Object Detection with CNN&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get a list of bounding boxe coordinates and a class probability attached to it. We pick the one with the highest probability as the output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;multiple-object-detector&quot;&gt;Multiple Object Detector&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have seen how a single object detector works, let’s fast forward to multiple object detection. In this case, we will be looking at Faster RCNN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An FRCNN is in some ways similar to a single object detector. The only addition is the presence of a Region Proposal Network, which proposes the regions where the likelihood of finding an object is extremely high. Once we get these regions from the RPN, we perform a pooling of the region of interests, and then as usual convert it into a fully connected layer and perform a classification for class label and regression for the bounding boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/frcnn.png&quot; alt=&quot;Faster RCNN&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tracking-without-bells-and-whistles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tracking-without-bells-and-whistles/</guid>
        
        <category>object detector</category>
        
        <category>faster rcnn</category>
        
        <category>object tracking</category>
        
        
        <category>Computer Vision</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Curious Case of Henry Molaison</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The human brain is one of the most important part of our body and it took millions and millions of years of evolution to achieve this level of perfection. And even after decades of studies, we have only managed to decode a small section of our brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century, one of the most well established theory about our brain is about the way it stores information i.e the concept of long term memory and short term memory and how our brain stores different informations in different manner. The story behind its discovery is very interesting. It all began from a person famously known as Patient HM in the world of neurosciencec. In order to completely understand the story, we need to travel back in time, back to America in the 1950s where our story takes place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-20th-century&quot;&gt;The 20th century&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the world war, there was rapid development in science and technology. But there was one area that was rather crude and not much developed and that is Neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The knowledge about our brain, mental health and other mental illnesses was not that developed and there weren’t any ethical barriers to performing medical procedures. Patients sufferring from mental illness  were locked up in what were known as mental asylums. They were experimented on and the treatments at the asylums were completely crazy and irrational. The patients were electrocuted with high voltages applied to their temples. The patients had to undergo regular hydrotherapy, where they were submerged in extremely cold water to calm them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/curioushenry/hydrotherapy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hydrotherapy in the 1940s. Credit: Alfred Eisenstaedt/Life Pictures/Getty Images&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hydrotherapy in the 1940s. Credit: Alfred Eisenstaedt/Life Pictures/Getty Images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We mostly hear about mental asyulms in horror movies, but this was the harsh reality back then. It was a crazy period and there wasn’t much knowledge or awareness about mental health. Then came another revolution in neurosurgery, the Lobotomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;lobotomy&quot;&gt;Lobotomy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This medical procedure was developed by doctors in Europe. The motto behind lobotomy was that if a certain part of the brain causes problem, just cut it out and everything will be fine. It was thought that cutting certain nerves in brain can fix the excess emotion and stabilize the person. A hole was drilled into the patient’s head from their eyeball socket and and they used to sever brain connections by using knives or by pouring ethanol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/curioushenry/lobotomy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A drawing from Dr. Walter Freeman’s book showing his lobotomy procedure&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A drawing from Dr. Walter Freeman’s book showing his lobotomy procedure&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lobotomy was hailed as an innovation, an instant cure for mental patients. There were more than 50,000 of these surgeries performed just in America. Soldiers suffering from PTSD due to the world war, perform Lobotomy and he’ll be instantly cured. If someone is emotionally unstable, perform lobotmy and they’ll be instantly cured. Of course, in reality, lobotomy was not exactly a cure. It was just cutting open the brain and mushing around with the brain tissues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“As those who watched the procedure described it, a patient would be rendered unconscious by electroshock. Freeman would then take a sharp ice pick-like instrument, insert it above the patient’s eyeball through the orbit of the eye, into the frontal lobes of the brain, moving the instrument back and forth. Then he would do the same thing on the other side of the face.” &lt;em&gt;-Quoted in the National Public Radio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did these procedures work? No, definitely not. There were very slim chances of surviving such a procedure. The success rate was less than 50% and even amongst those who survived, the lobotomy had negative effects on a patient’s personality, initiative, inhibitions, empathy and ability to function on their own. Those who survived were left as nothing more than empty shells unable to do anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;henry-molaison&quot;&gt;Henry Molaison&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henry Molaison, popularly known in the world of neuroscience as Patient HM is the foundation for all the knowledge we have about brain. Most of the knowledge that we have about our brain can be traced back to this person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/curioushenry/henry.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Molaison in 1953 before his surgery&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Molaison in 1953 before his surgery&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henry was born in Connecticut, U.S in 1929. After a bicycle injury at the age of 7, he started suffering from intractable epilepsy.
He had minor or partial seizures for many years, and then major or tonic-clonic seizures following his 16th birthday. He used to work on an assembly line but by the age of 27, he had become so incapacitated by his seizures that he could not work nor lead a normal life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doctors tried various remedies including high dosages of anticonvulsant medication but none of them yielded good results. Dr Scoville, the then neurosurgeon at the Hartford Hospital in Connecticut, decided to perform a lobotmy. Scoville had localized Molaison’s epilepsy to the left and right medial temporal lobes. On 1st September 1953, Molaison allowed surgeons to remove a thumb-sized section of tissue from each side of his brain. It was an experimental procedure that he and his surgeons hoped would quell the seizures wracking his brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there weren’t any strict ethical code for doctors during those times, the lobotomy was said to have been performed with the consent of the patient and his family. Scoville removed Molaison’s medial temporal lobes on both hemispheres including the hippocampus and most of the amygdala and entorhinal cortex, the major sensory input to the hippocampus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/curioushenry/hmbrain.png&quot; alt=&quot;HM's brain after the lobotomy&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;HM's brain after the lobotomy, Credit: Rochelle Bloom, Duke University &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, &lt;strong&gt;the surgery was successful&lt;/strong&gt;. Molaison’s seizure were abated and more controllable. But Scoville didn’t consider the implications of his surgery. Molaison was left with dense &lt;strong&gt;memory loss&lt;/strong&gt;. He suffered from what we now know as &lt;strong&gt;retrograde amnesia&lt;/strong&gt;. Obviously, this was not scientifically established back then in 1950s. Up until then, it had not been known that the hippocampus was even essential for making memories, and that if we lose both of them we will suffer an amnesia. Once this was realized, the findings were widely publicized so that this operation to remove both hippocampi would never be done again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Scoville realized his patient had become amnesic, he referred him to the eminent neurosurgeon Dr. Wilder Penfield and neuropsychologist Dr. Brenda Milner of Montreal Neurological Institute (MNI), who assessed him in detail. Penfield and Milner had already been conducting memory experiments on other patients and they quickly realized that Henry’s dense amnesia, his intact intelligence, and the precise neurosurgical lesions made him the perfect experimental subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;55 years&lt;/strong&gt;, Henry participated in numerous experiments, primarily at &lt;strong&gt;Massachusetts Institute of Technology&lt;/strong&gt; (MIT), where Professor Suzanne Corkin and her team of neuropsychologists assessed him. He died in December 2008 at the age of 82.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-research-on-molaison&quot;&gt;The Research on Molaison&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henry’s memory loss was far from simple. Firstly, he was &lt;strong&gt;unable to make any new memories&lt;/strong&gt; after his operation. He also had &lt;strong&gt;moderate retrograde amnesia&lt;/strong&gt; i.e he could not remember most events in the 1-2 year period prior to his surgery. In some cases, he couldn’t remember events upto 11 years before the time of surgery. He could remember some things — scenes from his childhood, some facts about his parents, and historical events that occurred before his surgery — but he was unable to form new memories. If he met someone who then left the room, within minutes he had no recollection of the person or their meeting. He was perpetually “trapped in the moment,” &lt;strong&gt;unable to recall anything beyond 30 seconds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scoville and Milner described their findings in their 1957 paper titled “Loss of recent memory after Bilateral Hippocampal Lesions”$^{[8]}$. They realized that only patients who had specific portions of their medial temporal lobes removed experienced memory problems. And, the more tissue removed, the more severe the memory impairment. The researchers noted patients’ amnesia was “curiously specific to the domain of recent memory.” This led to the understanding that complex functions such as learning and memory are tied to discrete regions of the brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henry lived for 55 years without acquiring any new declarative memories. His surgery, however, left intact other circuits that supported his nondeclarative memory, so he could &lt;strong&gt;learn new motor skills&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;acquire conditioned responses&lt;/strong&gt;.  He was a very happy and friendly person and always a delight to be with and to assess. He never seemed to get tired of doing what most people would think of as tedious memory tests, because they were always new to him! When he was at MIT, between test sessions he would often sit doing crossword puzzles, and he could do the same ones again and again if the words were erased, as to him it was new each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief summary of his condition is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Henry’s short-term memory was intact; whereas he failed to convert short-term memories into long-term memories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forgot new experiences after operation and inability to form new memories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;His semantic memory for prior to operation was intact (recalled historical facts, recognized relatives, good vocabulary) and had intact procedural memory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The episodic memory prior to operation showed deficits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;His IQ was above average&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;His language, reasoning, and perceptual capacities were normal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study of Molaison revolutionized the understanding of the organization of human memory. It has provided broad evidence for the rejection of old theories and the formation of new theories on human memory, in particular about its processes and the underlying neural structures. Some of the breakthrough discoveries$^{[8]}$ from his study are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Partition of memory into short-term and long-term memory processes, each part being mediated by a specialized memory circuit. It became evident from a series of cognitive tests that short-term memory is the immediate present. Its capacity is limited and fades immediately unless (a) We rehearse it or (b) convert it into a form that can be retained in long-term memory. Henry was able to use rehearsal but unable to convert short-term memories into long-term memories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/curioushenry/memory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Memory as we know it Now&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Memory as we know it Now&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Duration of short-term memory - Henry could easily and accurately perform the task when there was no delay between stimuli, however, the ability to differentiate between stimuli became harder as the gap between them got longer beyond 30s. At 60s, it was just a random performance. The abrupt breakdown in Henry’s performance between 30s and 60s showed that the duration of &lt;strong&gt;short-term memory last less than 60 seconds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Concept of semantic and episodic memory as being distinctly organized in brain - In case of Hnery, most details of unique events were lost (&lt;strong&gt;episodic, autobiographical memory&lt;/strong&gt;) but general knowledge of the world is preserved (&lt;strong&gt;semantic memory&lt;/strong&gt;), indicating that the anatomical substrates for these two forms of memory were distinct. We now know that the medial temporal-lobe structures are engaged in the initial encoding, storage, and retrieval of both kinds of memories. Then, during the process of consolidation, semantic memories become permanently established in the cortex while episodic, autobiographical-memory traces continue to depend on medial temporal-lobe structures indefinitely. Thus, the removal of this tissue from Henry’s brain left him devoid of autobiographical memories&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Henry’s spatial memory-declarative memory for spatial locations was deficient. It established the &lt;strong&gt;importance of the hippocampus for spatial learning&lt;/strong&gt;. However, after a few days, he could accurately draw the map of the house where he lived, means that other brain areas took over the job of encoding and storing that rich spatial information. This task depended on the parahippocampal gyrus, part of which remained in Henry’s brain on both sides. Hence, on rare occasions, he somehow compensated for the devastating effect of his hippocampal damage by mobilizing preserved brain structures and networks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Recognizing that learning can take place without awareness (&lt;strong&gt;non-declarative memory&lt;/strong&gt;) was one of the most significant advances. Henry learnt to use a walker. Dr. Milner introduced the idea that some memory processes were not hippocampus-dependent by showing that Henry’s error scores decreased across 3 days of testing on a motor skill-learning task, that is, mirror tracing. This discovery constituted the first experimental demonstration of preserved learning in amnesia. The “non-declarative memory” typically was not impaired in Henry’s case. Dr. Milner’s view was further strengthened by the touch-guided maze test, which was first demonstration within a single experiment, of impaired declarative learning (failure to learn the correct route) with preserved procedural i.e non-declarative learning.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A healthy hippocampus is essential for vividly recounting the details (recollection), but that it is not essential for simply recognizing a face, without identifying it or placing it in a context (familiarity)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Henry was able to produce conditioned responses in eye blink conditioning experiment, which helped to speculate that the conditioned memory, which was intact, was not mediated by medial temporal lobe.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The brain circuit responsible for odour detection (this bottle contains an odour) and odour intensity discrimination (this odour is stronger) is separate from the circuit that supports odor discrimination (this smells like cloves). Henry could not do latter. We now know that odor discrimination takes place in the front part of the parahippocampal gyrus, the amygdala, and the cortex around the amygdale.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;further-studies&quot;&gt;Further Studies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henry laid the foundation for all the future studies and he was the only patient who was lobotomized. Lobotomy was later banned in the 1970s due to it being “contrary to the principles of humanity”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Henry was not the only patient who was studied on. In the later decades there were several more patients who were under study for example, Kent Cochrane, who suffered from severe anterograde amnesia due to an accident in 1981. His semantic memory was intact but lacked episodic memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decades after this event. we still haven’t been able to completely grasp the workings of the human brain. But there has been a considerable growth in the amount of knowledge available to use. We are able to treat mental illness that were considered untreatable back in the 20th century. I beleive that in the future, we will be able to completey understand the workings of human brain and even supersede it. We have already been able to build neural networks which are able to identify and classify faces better than humans.
We have also managed to build mechanical systems using deep learning that are able to percieve better than humans. There is a lot to look forward to in the future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barbara Dury&lt;/em&gt;, Lobotomy: A Dangerous Fad’s Lingering effect on Mental Illness Treatment &lt;br /&gt;
https://www.retroreport.org/video/first-do-no-harm/&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ben Cosgrove&lt;/em&gt;, Strangers to Reason: LIFE Inside a Psychiatric Hospital, 1938 &lt;br /&gt;
https://www.retroreport.org/video/first-do-no-harm/&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tanya Lewis&lt;/em&gt;, Lobotomy: Definition, Procedure &amp;amp; History &lt;br /&gt;
https://www.livescience.com/42199-lobotomy-definition.html&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;National Public Radio&lt;/em&gt;, Frequently Asked Questions About Lobotomies &lt;br /&gt;
https://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=5014565&amp;amp;ps=rs&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jacopo Annese, Natalie M, Hauke Bartsch&lt;/em&gt;, Postmortem examination of patient H.M.’s brain based on histological sectioning and digital 3D reconstruction&lt;br /&gt;
https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms4122&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Barbara Dury&lt;/em&gt;, Lobotomy: A Dangerous Fad’s Lingering effect on Mental Illness Treatment &lt;br /&gt;
https://www.retroreport.org/video/first-do-no-harm/&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;William Scoville, Brenda Miller&lt;/em&gt;, Loss of recent memory after Bilateral Hippocampal Lesions&lt;br /&gt;
https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC497229/&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bigya Shah, Raman Deep Pattanayak, Rajesh Sagar&lt;/em&gt;, The study of patient henry Molaison and what it taught us over past 50 years: Contributions to neuroscience &lt;br /&gt;
https://www.jmhhb.org/article.asp?issn=0971-8990;year=2014;volume=19;issue=2;spage=91;epage=93;aulast=Shah&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/curious-case-of-henry-molaison/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/curious-case-of-henry-molaison/</guid>
        
        <category>cognition</category>
        
        <category>memory</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor. If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;html&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;ml-1 mr-1&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;target=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;_blank&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;fab fa-twitter&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;css&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-css highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#999988&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;font-style&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;italic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.highlight&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#a61717&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;#e3d2d2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;js&quot;&gt;JS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-js highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// alertbar later&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scroll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scrollTop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;280&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;.alertbar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fadeIn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;.alertbar&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dl&quot;&gt;'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fadeOut&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;python&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'redcarpet'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Redcarpet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;to_html&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;c&quot;&gt;C&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-c highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello World&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Jekyll</category>
        
        <category>tutorial</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
